<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An order of His Highness, with the advice and consent of His Privy Council, for continuing the Committee for the Army; and for the more orderly paiment, and issuing forth of the three moneths assessment of sixty thousand pounds by the moneth, commencing the 25th of March, 1657· At the council at Whitehall, the 14th of July 1657.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Lord Protector (1653-1658 : O. Cromwell)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A84418</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99870032</idno>
  <idno type="VID">169292</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240952343</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E7121A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E1065_36</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R211302</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99870032</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99870032e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A84418)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 169292)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 159:E1065[36])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An order of His Highness, with the advice and consent of His Privy Council, for continuing the Committee for the Army; and for the more orderly paiment, and issuing forth of the three moneths assessment of sixty thousand pounds by the moneth, commencing the 25th of March, 1657· At the council at Whitehall, the 14th of July 1657.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Lord Protector (1653-1658 : O. Cromwell)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>3, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Henry Hills and John Field, Printers to His Highness the Lord Protector,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1657]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">England and Wales. --  Army --  Pay, allowances, etc. --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="corporate_name">England and Wales. --  Committee for the Army --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-12 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-12 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:169292:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>depiction of the state arms of the Commonwealth (1649-60) consisting of the cross of St. George (patron saint of England) and the Irish harp</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>AN ORDER OF HIS HIGHNESS, With the Advice and Consent of His PRIVY COUNCIL, For continuing the Committee for the Army, and for the more Orderly Paiment, and Issuing forth of the three Moneths Assessment of sixty thousand pounds by the Moneth, com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mencing the 25<seg rend="sup">th</seg> of <hi>March,</hi> 1657.</head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>At the Council at <hi>Whitehall,</hi>
                  <date>the 14<seg rend="sup">th</seg> of <hi>July</hi> 1657.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas by an Order of His High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness and the Councel, of the <hi>13<seg rend="sup">th</seg>
               </hi> of <hi>June, 1657.</hi> in pursuance of a Proviso and Declaration, contained in one Act of this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent Parliament, Entituled, <hi>An Act for an Assessment upon <hi>England,</hi> at the Rate of threescore thousand Pounds by the Moneth, for three
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:169292:2"/> Moneths, from the 25<seg rend="sup">th</seg> day of <hi>March</hi> 1657. to the 24<seg rend="sup">th</seg> of <hi>June</hi> then next ensuing,</hi> it was Ordered, That the Receivers General for the respec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive Counties, Cities, Towns and Places, and every of them respectively, should, and they were thereby Authorized, and required from time to time, to make paiment of the severall Sums which should be by them Received, of all, and every Collector, and Sub-collector, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the said three Moneths Assessment, by ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue of the said Act, unto <hi>John Blackwell</hi> the younger, and <hi>Richard Deane,</hi> Esqs; Receivers Generall for the said whole three Moneths Assessment, at <hi>Guild-hall London,</hi> or where, or to whom they shall appoint, to be by them paid into, and Accompted for in the Receipt of His Highness Exchequer; For the more Orderly Managing, Levying, Paiment, Disposing, and Issuing forth of the Moneys, payable upon the said three Moneths Assessment for supply of the Forces of this Common-wealth: It is Ordered by His Highness the Lord Protector, by, and with the Advice and Consent of His Privy Councell; That the severall persons named and appointed by an Ordinance pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lished in Print, by Order of the <hi>28<seg rend="sup">th</seg>
               </hi> of <hi>January 1653.</hi> to be a Committee for the Army, or any three, or more of them, shall be, and are hereby Authorized and Impowred, to put in Executi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on all, and every such Powers, Authorities, Rules and Directions, for the Managing Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vying, Disposing, and Issuing forth of the said three Moneths Assessment for the purpose afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, as were by the said Ordinance, or by any Act, Ordinance, or Order therein mentioned, expressed to be given to the late Committee for
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:169292:2"/> the Army, for the bringing in, Receiving, Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sposing, and Issuing forth of the Assessments, and Moneys in that Ordinance mentioned.</p>
            <p>And it is further Ordered, That the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>surers at Wars, and also the severall and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective Commissioners, Receivers General, Collectors, sub-Collectors, and all other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons whatsoever, intrusted, or imploied in the Assessing, Collecting, Levying, Receiving, and Paying of the said three Moneths Assessment, or any part thereof, shall observe such Orders and Directions as shall from time to time be made, and given forth by the said Committee for the Army, or any three or more of them, in the due Execution of the Powers, and Trust hereby given and continued to them.</p>
            <p>Provided always, That none of the Powers hereby given or continued, shall extend, or be construed to extend, to Authorize or Impower the said Committee for the Army, or any other person or persons, to Raise, or Levy any of the Moneys aforesaid, by Free-Quarter, or quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering of Souldiers.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>Henry Scobell,</hi> Clerk of the Council.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed by <hi>Henry Hills</hi> and <hi>John Field,</hi> Printers to His Highness the Lord Protector. 1657.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>